A Guide to James Madison University Historic Photographs, 1919-ca. 2000: UA 0051
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
James Madison University Historic Photographs,
1909-ca. 2000
Special Collections, Carrier Library, James Madison University
UA 0051
1.8 cubic feet; 5 boxes
The James Madison University Historic Photographs, 1909-ca. 2000, comprises approximately 1700 photographs that depict notable events, activities, faculty, students, students groups, places, and everyday life at James Madison University and the surrounding community between 1909-ca. 2000.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection open to research. Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection. Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the James Madison University Special Collections Library to use this collection.
Acquisition Information
The photographs housed in this collection were contributed to Special Collections by individual donors, collected from JMU organizations and affiliates, or pulled from alumni collections by former Special Collections staff, from 1994-ca. 2007. Known donors include: Inez Roop, Bernice Catherine Jones, Charlotte Michael, Mrs. D. Patrick Snider, Mary Spitzer, Ethel Stevanus, Dr. Daniel McFarland, Craig Baugher, Fred Hilton, Jim Richardson, Milla Sue Wisecarver, and JMU Photography Services.
Administrative History
Photographs were donated by multiple sources. Due to the artificial nature of this collection, an administrative history does not apply.
Scope and Contents
The James Madison University Historic Photographs include photographs taken between 1909-ca. 2000, from the inception of university as the State Normal School for Women at Harrisonburg until the late 1990s. These photos depict notable events, faculty, students, student groups, student activities, building exteriors, building interiors, campus aerials, guest speakers, and everyday life at James Madison University.
Other Formats Available
Digitized photographs in this collection can be found here: https://www.lib.jmu.edu/special/jmu-historic-photos/
Index Terms
Subjects:
State Normal School for Women at Harrisonburg (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- History; State Normal and Industrial School for Women (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- History; State Teachers College at Harrisonburg (Harrisonburg, Va.) -- History; Madison College -- History; James Madison University -- History; James Madison University -- Buildings -- History; James Madison University -- Students -- History; James Madison University -- Faculty -- History; James Madison University -- Administration -- History
Genre and Form Terms:
Color photographs; Black-and-white photographs; Photographs; Negatives (photographs)
- Series 1: Historic Photographs, 1909-1985
  - Series 1: Aerial Views 1, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Aerial Views 2, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Anthony Seeger Campus School, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Archeological Digs, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Board of Visitors, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Buildings: Alumnae Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Buildings: Ashby Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Buildings: Bridgeforth Stadium, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Buildings: Carrier Library, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Buildings: Carrier Library Dedication, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Buildings: Cleveland Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Buildings: Convocation Center, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Buildings: Gibbons Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Buildings: Gifford Hall (Converse Hall), 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Buildings: Grafton-Stovall Theatre, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Buildings: Harrison Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Buildings: Hillcrest, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Buildings: Infirmary, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Buildings: Interiors, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Buildings: Interiors Dining Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Buildings: Interiors Dorms, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Buildings: Jackson Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Buildings: Johnson Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Buildings: Keezell Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Buildings: Library, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Buildings: Madison Memorial Library Interior, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Buildings: Madison Memorial Library Exterior, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Buildings: Maury Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Buildings: Miscellaneous 1, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Buildings: Miscellaneous 2, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Buildings: Residence Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Buildings: Sheldon Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Buildings: Sorority House, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Buildings: Spotswood Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Buildings: Varner House, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Buildings: Wayland Hall, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Buildings: Wilson Hall 1, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Buildings: Wilson Hall 2, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Ceremonies & Special Events 1, 1909-1985 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Ceremonies & Special Events 2, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ceremonies & Special Events 3, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Choir, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Community Involvement, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Faculty: Group, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Faculty and Staff Group, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Faculty: Individual 1, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Faculty: Individual 2, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Faculty and Staff Individual, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General Campus Views: Buildings and Grounds 1, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - General Campus Views: Buildings and Grounds 2, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - General Campus Views: Quad 1, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - General Campus Views: Quad 2, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - General Campus Views: With Students, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Glee Club, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Graduation: Senior Capping Founder's Day 1, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Graduation: Senior Capping Founder's Day 2, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Guest Speakers, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Homecoming, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Mace, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Madisonians, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - May Day 1, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - May Day 2, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - May Day 3, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Musical Groups & Activities 1, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Musical Groups & Activities 2, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Name Change, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Negatives, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Planetarium, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Postcards, 1909-1985 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Presidents: Burruss & Duke, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - President Carrier, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - President Carrier: Inauguration, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - President Miller, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Protesting, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Registration & Orientation, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - ROTC, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Royal Marching Dukes, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - 75th Anniversary, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Sports: Archery Baseball Golf Gymnastics, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Sports: Basketball Men's, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Sports: Basketball Women's, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Sports: Cheerleaders Fans Mascot 1, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Sports: Cheerleaders Fans Mascot 2, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Sports: Football, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Sports: Fencing Hockey and Lacrosse, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Sports: Soccer Swimming Track and Field, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Sports: Tennis Volleyball, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Student Teaching, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - Students: African American, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - Students: Artworks 1, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Students: Artworks 2, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Students: Business Classes, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Students: Classroom Work, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Students: Communications Work, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Students: Dance, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Students: Field Trips & Excursions, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Students: General Campus Life 1, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Students: General Campus Life 2, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Students: General Campus Life 3, 1909-1985 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Students: General Campus Life 1909:1918, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Students: General Campus Life Arriving and Departing, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Students: Health Science, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Students: Home Economics 1, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Students: Home Economics 2, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Students: Lab Work, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Students: Library Science, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Students: Miscellaneous Student Groups 1, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Students: Miscellaneous Student Groups 2, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Students: School Governance, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Students: Social Life 1, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Students: Social Life 2, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Students: Theatre, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Students: Theatre Open Air Theatre, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Students: Theatre Shakespeare Pageant of 1916, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - University Farm, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - WMRA, 1909-1985 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Series 2: Historic Photographs, 1985-ca. 2000
  - African American Greek Life, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Alumni, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Arboretum, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Bridge for the Stadium, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Buildings & Grounds- Maintenance, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Campus Views, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Carrier, Dr. Ronald, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Carrier Library, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Center for Entrepreneurship, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - College of Integrated Science and Technology, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Community Involvement, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Contemporary Gospel Singers (CGS), 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Dorms- Interior, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Dukettes, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Faculty: Individuals, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Flood of 1996, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Founder's Day, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Geology Lab, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Graduation, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Greek Life, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Guest Speaker, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Homecoming, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Living Sciences, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Madisonians, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Marching Royal Dukes, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - King, Martin Luther Birthday, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Minority Organizations, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Newman Lake, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Postcards, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Protests, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Quad, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Race Relations, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - ROTC, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - Snow Days, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Sonner Hall, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sports: Baseball, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sports: Cheerleading, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sports: Coaches, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sports: Mascot, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Sports: Basketball Women, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Students: Government Association (SGA), 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Students: General Campus Life, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Students: General Campus Life, Arriving & Departing, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Students: Relaxation, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Taylor Hall, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - University Recreation Center, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Valley Days, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Warren Hall, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Wilson Hall, 1985-ca. 2000 (Box 5, Folder 15)